adbutler.com 2019-12-22

# Privacy Statement

AdButler recognizes your right to confidentiality and is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather, how we use it, and how to correct or change it. You can expect to be notified of:

  * What personally identifiable information of yours is collected.
  * What organization is collecting the information.
  * How the information is used.
  * With whom the information may be shared.
  * What choices you have regarding the collection, use and distribution of the information.
  * What kinds of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under the company’s control. 
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

You should direct questions regarding this statement to any of our listed methods of contact: <https://adbutler.com/contact-us.spark>

## Your personal information

We do not collect personal information when you visit our site unless you signup for a service, place an order, register, complete a survey or enter a contest.

When you signup for a service, we will ask you for the following personal information: name and e-mail address. We may use your personal information to contact you for account purposes.

When you place an order (upgrade to a paid version of software), we will ask you for the following personal information: name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, and credit card number and its expiration date. This information is requested to verify your identity. This information is transmitted via a secure encrypted server using Transport Layer Security (TLS) encryption, more commonly known as HTTPS, the approved industry standard (see Security section below). We may use your personal information to contact you for account purposes.

When you submit feedback or questions via e-mail, or contact us for information about our Web site, we will request your name and e-mail address. We use this information solely to respond to your inquiries.

We share general demographic information with advertisers and partners as aggregated information that cannot be used in any way to identify you.

All performance statistics and data is kept private and not released to any of our partners without your permission. Occasionally, we may reference our own statistics, but the data will be an aggregate of our whole client base, and not identify any one party.

AdButler certifies that all personal information relating to its members and clients, including email addresses and personal information, will be kept confidential. We do not share, sell, rent or barter any identifiable personal information to any third party without your permission.

## Company information

You agree that AdButler may identify your company name and/or logo as an AdButler customer on client lists, marketing materials and/or press releases. If you wish to be excluded from this program, do so by emailing: "marketing AT adbutler.com".

## Security

AdButler uses Transport Layer Security (TLS) encryption, more commonly known as HTTPS, for all of the data that we send and receive. This ensures that all user data in transit is both safe and secure, and additionally only available to the intended recipients. This ensures that online transactions and the transmission of personal information such as credit card details are safe from third-party interception.

## Cookies

To better serve you, we use "cookies" to reduce the time required to login. A cookie is a small amount of information sent from a Web server to your computer. We use cookies to retrieve certain information you previously provided to AdButler, so that you do not need to reenter this information every time you login into the members area. Additionaly we use cookies to prevent multiple votes on our Web Poll and Survey services. Cookies are not used to access information entered on the secure server; this information can only be accessed when you enter your name and password. No other company has access to our cookies. We do not use the cookie to track your Internet activity once you leave AdButler.

We collect and process a variety of non-personally identifying information in order to prevent fraud and support and maintain a higher quality browsing experience for all users. We do not track individual users. 

#### AdButler Frequency Capping Cookie

  * Data Collected:
    * A non-personal ID that links to the zone and/or advertisement (not the individual)
    * A timestamp
  * Purpose of Cookie:
    * Ensure that a user does not see the advertisement repeatedly
  * Duration of Data Stored:
    * The duration for this cookie is set by the administrator within the AdButler interface each time it is used
  * Extent of Data Processing:
    * The data this cookie collects is not shared with any third parties and is used exclusively by AdButler for the reason mentioned above. This information cannot be used to uniquely identify an individual.

#### AdButler Conversion Tracking Cookie

  * Data Collected:
    * A non-personal ID that links to the zone and/or advertisement (not the individual)
  * Purpose of Cookie:
    * Allow attribution of an advertisement to a desired goal. This does not track an individual, only the source advertisement
  * Duration of Data Stored:
    * This cookie expires within 180 days
  * Extent of Data Processing:
    * The data this cookie collects is not shared with any third parties and is used exclusively by AdButler for the purpose mentioned above. This information cannot be used to uniquely identify an individual.

These advertising cookies are intended to improve the browsing experience by reducing the number of repeating ads you see. The advertising cookies also allow an advertiser to attribute the viewing of an ad to an action on the destination website. This is attribution is not tied to an individual, and there is no tracking of an individual involved. 

To clear your cookies: 

  * Open your browser settings or preferences (depending on your browser)
  * Search for _Cookies_
  * Select _Clear browsing data_
  * Select _Cookies and other site data_ or _Clear Data_ (depending on your browser)
  * Confirm the clearing of the cookie data

A small portion of the ads served on mobile apps through AdButler incorporate personalization by select partners. This personalization is meant to provide ads more relevant to your interests. If you prefer not to have personalized ads in mobile app advertisements, you can reset your advertiser ID on your mobile device, however this may result in advertisements less suited to your interests. 

To reset your advertising ID on an Android device: 

  * Open your device settings
  * Select/tap _Google settings_
  * Select/tap _Ads_
  * Select/tap _Reset advertising ID_
  * Confirm that you want to reset your advertising ID

To reset your advertising ID on an iOS device: 

  * Open your device settings
  * Select/tap _Privacy_
  * Select/tap _Advertising_
  * Select/tap _Reset advertising identifier_
  * Confirm that you want to reset your advertising ID

## Your choice/opt out

AdButler provides you with the opportunity to remove your personal information from our database and opt out of receiving communications from us at any time. Login to the members section and delete any products that you have signed for (See FAQ for more information).

If you would like to opt out of all AdButler cookies, you can do so [here](https://www.adbutler.com/cookie-opt-out.spark).

AdButler provides you with the opportunity to update or change any information you previously provided. Please login to the members area and make your changes (See FAQ for more information).

## Your consent

By using our Web site, you consent to AdButler collecting and using this information as outlined here. If we ever change our privacy policy, we will post any changes on this page so you are always aware of the information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it.

## Bot/Data Collection

AdButler and its affiliates will never affix any spybot or data collection software to any of its products.

## Your comments/how to reach us

If you have questions or comments about AdButler's privacy policy, please feel free to [contact us](https://www.adbutler.com/contact-us.spark).
